Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz research materials on New Deal art
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz research materials on New Deal Art
1931-1999
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Park, Marlene
5.8 linear feet
The Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz research files on New Deal art are dated 1931-1999 and measure 5.8 linear feet. The research files document New Deal art projects and artists through some original correspondence with artists, printed material, interview transcripts, and several sound recordings of interviews with artists of the period. Subject files relate to WPA era art and art projects; many contain numerous photocopies of records from the Personnel Records Center and the U. S. Treasury Relief Arts Projects now in the custody of the National Archives and Records Administration.
Provenance
The Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz research materials on New Deal Art were donated to the Archives in 1999 by art historians Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Art historians Marlene Park and husband Gerald E. Markowitz conducted research on New Deal art projects. Their work resulted in an exhibition "New Deal for Art: The Government Projects of the 1930's with Examples from New York City and State" (1977) and a catalog with the same title. 7), and a book, Democratic Vistas: Post Offices and Public Art in the New Deal (1984). Both were on the faculty of the John Jay College of Criminal Justice. Marlene Park served on the Public Art Preservation Committee from 1979-1982.
Scope and Content Note
The Marlene Park and Gerald E. Markowitz research files on New Deal art are dated 1931-1999 and measure 5.8 linear feet. The research files document New Deal art projects and artists through some original correspondence with artists, printed material, interview transcripts, and several sound recordings of interviews with artists of the period. Subject files relate to WPA era art and art projects; many contain numerous photocopies of records from the Personnel Records Center and the U. S. Treasury Relief Arts Projects now in the custody of the National Archives and Records Administration.
The collection consists primarily of artists' files documenting the WPA, The National Personnel Records Center, the Public Art Preservation Committee, and the U.S. Treasury Relief Art Project. Also found are lists of artists arranged by category, correspondence, transcripts of interviews, printed material, exhibition catalogs, monographs, photographs, slides, and sound recordings. Among the artists are: Charles Alston, Will Barnet, Ilya Bolotowsky, Louis Bouche, James Brooks, Charles Burchfield, Paul Cadmus, Minna Citron, Robert Cronbach, Hugo Gellert, Adloph Gottlieb, Leo Katz, Roy King, Albert Kotin, Edward Lanning, Ethel Magafan, William Palmer, Anton Refregier, Philip Reisman, Lincoln Rothschild, Joseph Solman, Harry Sternberg, Stuyvesant Van Veen, and Marion Walton.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series:
Series 1: Artists' Files, 1931-1999 (Boxes 1-5, 7, OV 8-10; 4.8 linear feet)
Series 2: Subject Files, 1934-1999 (Boxes 5, 7, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Printed Material, 1977-1989 (Box 5; 0.2 linear ft.)
Series 4: Sound Recordings, 1974-1976 (Boxes 5-6; 0.3 linear ft.)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Alston, Charles Henry, 1907-1977; Barnet, Will, 1911-; Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1907-1981; Bouché, Louis, 1896-1969; Brooks, James, 1906-; Burchfield, Charles Ephraim, 1893-1967; Cadmus, Paul, 1904-1999; Citron, Minna Wright, 1896-1991; Cronbach, Robt.(Robert M.), 1908-; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985; Gottlieb, Adolph, 1903-1974; Katz, Leo, 1887-1982; King, Roy E., 1903-; Kotin, Albert, 1907-1980; Lanning, Edward P.; Magafan, Ethel, 1915 or 6-1993; Palmer, William, 1906-1987; Refregier, Anton, 1905-; Reisman, Philip, 1904-; Rothschild, Lincoln, 1902-; Solman, Joseph, 1909-2008; Sternberg, Harry, 1904-2001; Van Veen, Stuyvesant; Walton, Marion, b. 1899; National Personnel Records Center (U.S.); United States. Work Projects Administration
Subjects-Topical:
Federal aid to the arts
Types of Materials:
Interviews; Photographs; Sound recordings; Transcripts
Names:
Markowitz, Gerald E.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Artists' Files, 1931-1999, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-5, 7, OV 8-10; 4.8 linear feet)
  Artists' files include correspondence, transcripts of interviews, printed material, exhibition catalogs, monographs, photographs, slides, and audio recordings.
  - Aarons - Ault, 1936-1990, undated (Box 1)
  - Alston, Charles, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Amateis, Edmond Romulus, 1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Archer, Edmund Minor, 1938-1939, undated (Box 1)
  - Arnest, Bernard, 1979, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 1)
  - Bairnsfather - Bywaters, 1936-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Baker, Mildred, 1937-1976 (Box 1)
  - Bannarn, Henry W., 1998-1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Barnet, Will, 1972-1983 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Herbert, 1983-1986, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 1)
  - Barone, Antonio, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Barthe, Richmond, undated (Box 1)
  - Baum, Max, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Beaulaurier, Leo J., 1979-1980, undated (Box 1)
  - Bell, Enid, 1978-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Bengelsdorf, Rosalind, 1981, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Biddle, George, 1978-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - Billings, Henry, 1979-1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Bengelsdorf, Rosalind, 1938-1981, undated (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Henry, 1972-1986, undated (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Theresa, 1979-1990 (Box 1)
  - Bessemer, Auriel, 1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Biberman, Edward, 1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Isabel, 1938-1977, undated (Box 1)
  - Binford, Julien, 1941-1974 (Box 1)
  - Blakeslee, Sarah (Speight), 1939 (Box 1)
  - Blanch, Lucille, 1941-1976 (Box 1)
  - Bloch, Julius, 1983, undated (Box 1)
  - Bloch, Lucienne, 1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Block, Dorothy, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Block, Lou, 1975, undated (Box 1)
  - Blume, Peter, 1979-1992 (Box 1)
  - Blumenschein, Ernest L., 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bodin, Paul, 1974, undated (Box 1)
  - Bohrod, Aaron, 1979-1985 (Box 1)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1976-1987, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Bouche, Louis, 1946-1993, undated (Box 1)
  - Brenner, Henri, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Bromberg, Manuel, 1945-1995, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, James, 1974-1995, undated (Box 1)
  - Browne, Byron, 1975-1991, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Burchfield, Charles E., 1928-1967, undated (Box 1)
  - Burke, Selma, 1962-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Busa, Peter, 1946-1976, undated (Box 1)
  - Calder - Custer, 1935-1987, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Cadmus, Paul, 1934-1984, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 10) (Box 1)
  - Calfee, William H., 1978-1980, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Callahan, Kenneth, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Canade, Vincent, 1931-1963 (Box 1)
  - Canepa, Tito, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
  - Carter, Clarence, 1938-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Carton, Norman, 1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Cecere, Gaetano, 1935-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Celentano, Daniel R., 1934-1980, undated (Box 1)
  - Champainer, Abram (Box 1)
  - Chavez, Edward, 1936-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Cheever, William Abbott, 1966-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Cherry, Herman, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Citron, Minna, 1940-1991, undated (Box 1)
  - The Collaborative, Gellert and Van Veen, undated (Box 1)
  - Constant, George, 1944-1974 (Box 1)
  - Cook, Howard, 1979-1983, undated (Box 1)
  - Covey, Arthur, 1936-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Coye, Lee Brown, 1975, undated (Box 1)
  - Crichlow, Ernest, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Crimi, Alfred D., 1934-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Crockwell, Douglass, 1934-1977, undated (Box 1)
  - Cronbach, Robert, 1940-1997, undated (Box 1)
  - Cunningham, Ben, 1937-1979, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1)
  - Curry, John Steuart, undated (Box 1)
  - Dalstrom - Duncan, 1935-1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Daugherty, Charles M., 1938-1979 (Box 2)
  - Daugherty, James, 1934-1998, undated (Box 2)
  - Davis, Charles, undated (Box 2)
  - Davis, Faye (Mrs. George Prout), 1979 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Lew E., 1940-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Davis, Stuart, 1931-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Day, Horace, 1940-1979 (Box 2)
  - De Brennecke, Nena, 1939-1942 (Box 2)
  - De Marco, Jean, 1979, undated (Box 2)
  - De Rivera, Jose, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Dehn, Adolf, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Delaney, Joseph, 1968-1999, undated (Box 2)
  - Deluce, Donald, 1941-1990, undated (Box 2)
  - Diller, Burgoyne, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Dohanos, Stevan, 1979-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Dolwick, William A., 1938-1979 (Box 2)
  - Donneson, Seena, undated (Box 2)
  - Douglas, Aaron, 1971-1979 (Box 2)
  - Dows, Olin, 1941-1981, undated (Box 2)
  - Driggs, Elsie, 1934-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Dyczkowski, Eugene M., 1976 (Box 2)
  - Earley, Mary, 1940-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Eckhardt, Edris, 1936-1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Edie - Evett, 1938-1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Ehrich, William, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Esman, Betty, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Etnier, Stephen, 1938-1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Everett, Eugenia, 1931-1982, undated (Box 2)
  - Evergood, Philip, 1943, undated (Box 2)
  - Fabion - Fyfe, 1936-1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Faggi, John, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Felipe, Juan de, 1991, undated (Box 2)
  - Fiene, Ernest, 1937-1991 (Box 2)
  - Fitzgerald, Edmond J., 1979-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Fogel, Seymour, 1940-1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Fredenthal, David, 1941-1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Fredericks, Marshall M., 1979-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Don, undated (Box 2)
  - Freund, Louis, 1978-1979, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 2)
  - Fruhauf, Aline, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Galgiany - Gussow, 1936-1990, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 2)
  - Gates, Robert Franklin, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Geissbuhler, Arnold, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Gellert, Hugo, 1936-1986 undated (Box 2)
  - German-American History, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Gershoy, Eugenie, 1975-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Gibbs, Maurine M., 1939-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Gikow, Ruth, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Glannon, Edward, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Glickman, Maurice, 1940-1977, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 2)
  - Glinsky, Vincent, 1936-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Goddelman, Aaron, 1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Gonzalez, Xavier, 1979-1993, undated (Box 2)
  - Goreleigh, Rex, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Gorelick, Boris, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Gorky, Arshile, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1941, undated (Box 2)
  - Gottlieb, Harry, 1975-1983, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 2)
  - Greco, Frank, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Greenwood, Grace and Marion, 1939-1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Gropper, William, 1934-1977, undated (Box 2)
  - Gross, Chaim, 1935-1991, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 2)
  - Gussow, Roy, 1967-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Guston, Phillip, 1974-1979 (Box 2)
  - Gwathmey, Robert, 1979-1996, undated (Box 2)
  - Haines, Richard, 1979, 1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Halberstadt, Ernst, 1978-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Halfant - Hutson, 1934-1997, undated (Box 2)
  - Hancock, Walker, 1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Harriton, Abraham, 1974, undated (Box 2)
  - Hart, Agnes, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Hartman, Bertram, 1995, undated (Box 2)
  - Hebald, Milton, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Hecht, Zolten, 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - Helfant, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Henricksen, Ralph, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Hershey, Samuel F., 1977, 1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Hirsch, Stefan, 1943-1997, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 2)
  - Hogue, Alexandre, 1979-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Holbrook, Hollis, 1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Horn, Axel, 1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Horn, Milton, 1968-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Houser, Lowell, 1937-1992 (Box 2)
  - Hurd, Peter, 1938-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Howard, Robert B., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Ipcar, Dahlov, undated (Box 2)
  - Jackman - Jones, 1935-1942, undated (Box 2)
  - Jacobi, Eli, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Jamieson, Mitchell, 1966-1979 (Box 2)
  - Japanese Artists, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Avery, 1939-1980 (Box 2)
  - Jones, Amy, 1938-1988, undated (Box 3)
  - Jones, Wendell, 1938-1989, undated (Box 3)
  - Kachinsky - Krusen, 1936-1984, undated (Box 3)
  - Kassoy, Bernard, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Katz, Leo, 1935-1992 (Box 3)
  - Katz, Raymond A., 1951-1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Kauffman, Andrene, 1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Keller, Charles, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1975, undated (Box 3)
  - The Kentucky Review, 1988 (Box 3)
  - King, Roy E., 1939-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Knight, Frederic C., 1934-1980, undated (Box 3)
  - Kotin, Albert, 1938-1982, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 3)
  - Kramer, Reuben, 1977-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Krause, Erik Hans, 1975-1976, undated (Box 3)
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1940 (Box 3)
  - La More, Chet, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Lo Medico, Thomas G., 1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Labaudt - Lyohn, 1935-1988, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 3)
  - Lambdin, Robert L., 1935-1980, undated (Box 3)
  - Laning, Edward, 1937-1992, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 3)
  - Lantz, Michael, 1942-1980, undated (Box 3)
  - Lasker, Joe, 1979-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1933-1986 (Box 3)
  - Lawrence, Jacob, 1945-1976 (Box 3)
  - Lazzari, Pietro, 1941-1979 (Box 3)
  - Lenson, Michael, 1993, undated (Box 3)
  - Levi, Julian, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Levit, Herschel, 1945-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Lewis, Norman, 1975-1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Lichtner, Schomer, 1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Lishinsky, Abe, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Locke, Charles, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Lockwood, Ward, 1937-1980, undated (Box 3)
  - Loew, Michael, 1975-1976, undated (Box 3)
  - Lonergan, John, 1939-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Lowry, Mina, 1936-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Lozowick, Louis, 1976, undated (Box 3)
  - Mac Tarian - Mc Millen, 1937-1939, undated (Box 3)
  - Mc Cosh, David, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Mc Mahon, Audrey, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Mc Vey, William M., 1974-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Maduro - Myers, 1933-1986, undated (Box 3)
  - Magafan, Ethel, 1938-1993, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 3)
  - Mangravite, Peppino, 1935-1976, undated (Box 3)
  - Marcus, Bernard, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Maril, Herman, 1977-1986 (Box 4)
  - Marsh, Reginald, 1935-1982, undated (Box 4)
  - Martin, Fletcher, 1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Martyl (Schweig Langsdorf), 1939-1980 (Box 4)
  - Mayer, Henrik Martin, 1936-1980, undated (Box 4)
  - Mayer, Jessie Hull, 1938-1980, undated (Box 4)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Mechau, Frank, 1937-1972, undated (Box 4)
  - Meltzer, Doris, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Mendelowitz, Daniel M., 1941-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Mexican Murals, 1933-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - Miller, Barse, undated (Box 4)
  - Nagai - Norling, 1936-1980, undated (Box 4)
  - Neel, Alice, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Newell, James Michael, 1934-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Newell, G. Glen, 1937-1941, undated (Box 4)
  - Ney, Bill, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Nickerson, Ruth (Mrs. Edmund Greacen), 1965-1983, undated (Box 4)
  - Nisita, Carlo, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, 1934-1976, undated (Box 4)
  - Oakley, Violet, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Obertueffer - Overby, 1934-1940, undated (Box 4)
  - Olmstead, Anna, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Ormo, Bela, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Pages, Jean, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Palmer, William, 1937-1988, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 4)
  - Parducci - Putnam, 1937-1940, undated (Box 4)
  - Parish, Betty Waldo, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Patri, Giacomo, 1982-1995, undated (Box 4)
  - Pels, Albert, 1976, undated (Box 4)
  - Penney, James, 1972-1984, undated (Box 4)
  - Perry, Mary, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Peters, Carl W., 1937-1998, undated (Box 4)
  - Picken, George, 1937-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Pollock, Merlin F., 1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Poor, Anne, 1976-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Prestopino, Gregorio, 1974-1984, undated (Box 4)
  - Putnam, Wallace, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Raymand - Rush, 1935-1982, undated (Box 4)
  - Ralston, J. K., 1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Raymond, Evelyn, 1982-1984, undated (Box 4)
  - Refregier, Anton, 1938-1997, undated (Box 4)
  - Refregier, Anton (San Francisco), 1953-1980, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 4)
  - Refregier, Anton,(writing by Gladys M. Kinkel), 1969 (Box 4)
  - Reisman, Philip, 1946-1999, undated (Box 4)
  - Rickey, George, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Rivera, Diego, 1937-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - Robus, Hugo, 1943, undated (Box 4)
  - Rogers, Charles B., 1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Romano, Umberto, 1979-1982, undated (Box 4)
  - Ronnebeck, Louise E., 1938-1998, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 10) (Box 4)
  - Rosenthal, Tony, 1975, undated (Box 4)
  - Roszak, Theodore, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Rothschild, Lincoln, 1965-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - Ruellan, Andree, 1913-1993, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 4)
  - Russin, Robert I., 1939-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Saalburg - Sloan, 1937-1982, undated (Box 4)
  - Saarinen, Lilian Swann, undated (Box 4)
  - Samerjan, George, 1965-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Sardeau, Helene, 1973-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - Scaravaglione, Concetta, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Schanker, Louis, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Scheuch, Harry W., 1940-1979 (Box 4)
  - Schreiber, Georges, 1934-1974, undated (Box 4)
  - Schwartz, William S., 1979-1984 (Box 4)
  - Scime, Pascal J., 1976 (Box 4)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1934-1979, undated (Box 5)
  - Shahn, Bernarda Bryson, 1934-1976 (Box 5)
  - Shane, Frederick E., 1979, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Sheets, Millard (Box 5)
  - Singer, Clyde, 1936-1979, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Siporin, Mitchell, 1936-1990, undated (Box 5)
  - Sisti, Anthony, 1940-1976 (Box 5)
  - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1976, undated (Box 5)
  - Slivka, David, 1963-1980, undated (Box 5)
  - Slobodkina - Sykes, 1938-1982, undated (Box 5)
  - Sokole, Miron, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Solman, Joseph, 1974-1984, undated (Box 5)
  - Soyer, Moses, 1934-1974, undated (Box 5)
  - Soyer, Raphael, 1975-1979, undated (Box 5)
  - Speight, Francis, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Starr, Maxwell B., 1934-1976 (Box 5)
  - Stea, Cesare, 1976, undated (Box 5)
  - Stenbery, Algot, 1939-1975, undated (Box 5)
  - Sternberg, Harry, 1979-1992, undated (Box 5)
  - Sterne, Maurice, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Stewart, Albert, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Swiggett, Jean, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Tabor - Turzak, 1935-1941, undated (Box 5)
  - Taylor, John W., 1979-1988 (Box 5)
  - Thomas, Allan, 1937-1980, undated (Box 5)
  - Thomas, Lenone, undated (Box 5)
  - Thrash, Dox, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Thwaites, Charles W., 1944-1979, undated (Box 5)
  - Tingler, Chester J., 1939, undated (Box 5)
  - Tobey, Alton S., 1938-1980, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 10) (Box 5)
  - Tobias, Abraham, 1952-1999, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 5)
  - Tompkins, Alan, 1938-1979 (Box 5)
  - Toney, Anthony, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Tracy, Elizabeth, 1976-1979 (Box 5)
  - Treadwell, Helen, undated (Box 5)
  - Ulreich, Eduard Buk, 1940-1942, undated (Box 5)
  - Valentine, F. B., 1975, undated (Box 5)
  - Van Koert - Vytlacil, 1938-1984, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Van Veen, Stuyvesant, 1937-1981, undated (Box 5)
  - Vander Sluis, George, 1941-1980 (Box 5)
  - Varga, Margit, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Various, Federal Works Agency, 1937-1941 (Box 5)
  - Vogel, Joseph, 1992, undated (Box 5)
  - Vullo, James, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Wahl, Theodore, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Walker - Works, 1935-1985, undated (Box 5)
  - Walter, Jennings, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Walton, Marion, 1940-1992, undated (Box 5)
  - Ward, Lynd, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Weber, Max, 1983, undated (Box 5)
  - Werner, Nat, 1978-1980, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Weschler, Anita, 1939-1996, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 5)
  - Weston, Harold, 1979-1980, undated, (oversized material housed in OV 9) (Box 5)
  - White, Charles, 1975, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Winter, Lumen Martin, 1942-1980, undated (Box 5)
  - Wollins, Joseph, 1947-1989, undated (Box 5)
  - Yavano - Zorach, 1937-1985, undated (Box 5)
  - Zorach, William, 1936-1977, undated (Box 5)
  - Oversized Material from Artists' Files (Box 7)
    Benglesdorf, Rosalind (from Box 1)
    Bolotowsky, Ilya (from Box 1)
    Bromberg, Manuel (from Box 1)
    Browne, Byron (from Box 1)
    Calder - Custer (from Box 1)
    Calfee, William H. (from Box 1)
    Carter, Clarence (from Box 1)
    Cunningham, Ben (from Box 1)
    Freund, Louis (from Box 2)
    Gottlieb, Harry (from Box 2)
    Laning, Edward (from Box 3)
    Magafan, Ethel (from Box 3)
    Refregier, Anton (from Box 4)
    Shane, Frederick E.(from Box 4)
    Singer, Clyde (from Box 4)
    Van Koert - Vytlacil (from Box 5)
    Van Veen, Stuyvesant (from Box 5)
    Werner, Nat (from Box 5)
    White, Charles (from Box 5)
  - Oversized Material from Artists' Files (Box OV 8)
    Arnest, Bernard (from Box 1)
    Barnett, Herbert (from Box 1)
    Cadmus, Paul (from Box 1)
    Galgiany - Gussow (from Box 2)
    Glickman, Maurice (from Box 2)
    Gross, Chaim (from Box 2)
    Hirsch, Stefan (from Box 2)
    Kotin, Albert (from box 3)
  - Oversized Material from Artists' Files (Box OV 9)
    Labaudt - Lyon (from Box 3)
    Palmer, William (from Box 3)
    Ruellan, Andree (from Box 4)
    Ronnebeck, Louise E.(from Box 4)
    Tobias, Abraham (from Box 5)
    Weschler, Anita
    Weston, Harold (from Box 5)
  - Oversized Material from Artists' Files, Tobey, Alton S., 1973-1980, undated, (from Box 4) (Box OV 10)
- Subject Files, 1934-1999, Series 2:; (Boxes 5, 7, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet)
  Subject files include documentation of WPA, The National Personnel Records Center, the Public Art Preservation Committee, and Treasury Relief Art Project. Most files include correspondence and printed material.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - An American Group, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Art Dealers, Various, 1980-1999 (Box 5)
  - Artist in Residence, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Easel Painters, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Inventory of Artists' Files by Park and Markowitz, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Legislative Resolution, New York State, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Lists of Artists, undated (Box 5)
  - Murals, 1937-1941, 1980, undated (Box 5)
  - National Personnel Records Center, 1976-1997 (Box 5)
  - New York State Artists, by City, 1981, undated (Box 5)
  - Obituaries, Abbott - Rothschild, 1989-1993 (Box 5)
  - Public Art Preservation Committee, Resource Center, 1976-1984, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Public Works of Art Project, 1934, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Sculptors, undated (Box 5)
  - Syracuse University Library, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Treasury Relief Art Project, New York State Artists, 1935-1936 (Box 5)
  - Women, 1999, (oversized material housed in OV 10) (Box 5)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1936-1981 (Box 5)
  - Oversized Material from Subject Files (Box 7)
    - Public Art Preservation Committee, 1980, undated, (from Box 5) (Box 7)
    - Women, 1999, (from Box 5) (Box OV 10)
- Printed Material, 1977-1989, Series 3:; (Box 5; 0.2 linear ft.)
  Exhibition catalogs include New Deal for Art: The Government Projects of the 1930's with Examples from New York City and State (1977) by Park and Markowitz, and their book, Democratic Vistas: Post Offices and Public Art in the New Deal (1984.) "The Artists" is a 53-page chapter with footnotes about New Deal art; the title of the book and its author are unknown.
  - Book, Democratic Vistas, 1984 (Box 5)
  - "Chapter 4, The Artists," undated (Box 5)
  - Catalogues, 1977-1989 (Box 5)
  - Magazine, Timeline, 1989 (Box 5)
- Sound Recordings, 1974-1976, Series 4:; (Boxes 5-6; 0.3 linear ft.)